Okay. Let's look at the results of some A/A
好 现在让我们来看一些
tests on click-through-probability.
点击概率 A/A 测试的结果
Since we've already done the analytics calculation for
由于我们已经完成了对点击概率的分析结算
click-through-probability, we'll be able to compare the empirical results
我们可以将实证结果
to the analytic results.
与分析结果进行对比
But you can also use A/A tests in cases where you weren't able to do an analytic
但在你无法进行分析计算时
calculation.
你也可以使用 A/A 测试
Now, there are three main things you can do, using A/A testing, and
使用 A/A 测试 你主要可以做三件事情
I'm going to go through an example of each of them.
我会为每一种给出一个示例
First, if you already have an analytic calculation of your confidence interval,
首先 如果你已经对置信区间完成的分析计算
you can check your A/A test results to see if you're getting what you expect.
你可以检查 A/A 测试结果是否符合你的预期
This functions as a kind of sanity check.
这是一种完整性检查功能
If you're getting results that are not what you expect,
如果你得到的结果不符合你的预期
this indicates that something is wrong with your calculations.
这就表明你的计算出了错
Maybe you made an invalid assumption about the distribution of your data.
可能你对数据分布的假设是无效的
Second, if you are willing to make an assumption about the distribution of
第二 如果你想要对指标分布进行假设
your metric, but you weren't able to estimate the variance analytically,
但是不能分析估计方差
you can estimate the variance empirically, and
你可以通过实证预计方差
then use your assumption about the distribution to calculate the confidence
然后用你关于分布的假设
interval the same way we did before.
按照之前的方式计算置信区间
And third, if you don't want to make any assumptions about your data, you can
第三 如果你不想对数据做出任何假设
directly estimate a confidence interval from the results of the A/A tests.
你可以直接从 A/A 测试的结果中估计置信区间
Let's start with this first use case.
现在让我们先来讲第一种使用案例
Let's say we run 20 experiments, each running on 0.5% of our traffic.
比如说我们运行 20 次实验 每次实验针对流量的 0.5%
Then, we run another 20, each on 1% of our traffic and 10 more, each on 5%.
然后我们再运行 20 次实验 每次针对 1% 的流量 然后是 10次 每次针对 5%
All of these are A/A tests, with no difference between the two groups.
这些都是 A/A 测试 因为两者之间没有区别
For the sake of simplicity,
为了方便起见
I'm going to say that each of these 20 experiments had 50 users in each group.
我假设这 20 次实验 每次每组有 50 名用户
In reality, you might see around 50 users due to the randomization, but
在现实中 由于随机分配 你可能有大约 50 名用户
I'm going to say that each group had exactly 50,
而我这里假设每个组刚好是 50 名用户
just to make the calculations a little easier.
这样让计算会更加轻松点
Similarly, each of these experiments had 100 users per group.
相似地 这里每次实验每个组有 100 名用户
And each of these experiments had 500.
而这个实验是 500
Now let's say we analyzed each of these experiments using the same methods as
假设说我们已经用了第一课中的方法
in lesson one.
分析了每次实验
How many of them would you expect to see a statistically significant difference
那在置信度为 95% 的情况下 你认为在多少实验中
between the two groups at the 95% confidence level?
两组间会出现具有统计显著性的区别？
Even though there was no difference between the two groups,
即便这两组间并没有差别
remember that in a 95% confidence interval,
请记得在 95% 的置信区间中
the true value, in this case zero, will only be captured 95% of the time.
真正的值 这里为零 只会在 95% 的情况中出现
That means that out of 20 experiments,
也就是说在 20 次实验中
we expect to see one significant difference on average.
我们预计会看到平均一个显著差别
Of course, for an individual group of 20 experiments, it wouldn't be that
当然 对 20 次实验来讲
surprising to see zero or two, or some other number of significant results.
发现没有或者两个 或者其他数量的显著结果也是不奇怪的
Now, let's say that this Google spreadsheet shows the actual results of
显著 假设说这个 Google 电子表格
the experiment.
展示了实验的实际结果
This column shows the click-through-probability measured for
这一栏显示的是测量得到的第一组的点击概率
group one and this column shows what was measured for group two.
这一栏显示的是第二组的
If I scroll down, I can also see the results for
然后我下滑 可以在底部看到
the 1% experiments here and the 5% experiments at the bottom.
1% 实验和 5% 实验的结果
Now, if I analyze these numbers using the methods from lesson one,
现在 如果我使用第一课的方法分析这些数字
then I find that one experiment in the smallest group is significant and
我发现在最小的一组实验中有一个显著结果
zero in each of the other two.
另外两组为零
That's not terribly surprising.
这个不奇怪
If I had seen, say, five positives in one of the groups, then that would be
如果我在某一组中有五个正面结果
a sign that something was wrong with the set-up of the experiment, or
那就说明我们的实验设置或者假设
in the assumptions that I made.
可能有些问题
I'm not going to step through that calculation, but there's a sheet linked
我不会具体进行计算
in the instructor's note that has the calculation carried out.
讲师注释中提供了表格的连接 其中说明了计算过程
Another thing we can check about the A/A tests is whether the differences follow
然后我们用 A/A 测试进行的另一项检查
the distribution we expect.
是这个差异是否符合我们预期的分布
To do that, I'll insert a third column which contains the difference between
为此 我插入了第三栏
the two groups for each experiment.
显示每次实验两组之间的差异
One thing to check is whether the differences
其中要检查的一项是
are following a normal distribution as we expect.
这种差异是否按我们的预期符合正态分布
For the smallest experiments, the distribution looks fairly normal, but
对最小的实验组来说 分布看着像是正态的
for the other two it doesn't.
但是另外两组不是
However, I'd say that this is probably due to the fact
我觉得这很可能是因为
that we didn't run that many experiments.
我们并没有进行太多的实验
For 20 data points, this could be the result of a normal distribution and
对于 20 个数据点来说 结果可能是正态分布
remember this one had only ten data points.
但要记得 这个只有十个数据点
Another thing that these plots show is that the distribution is getting
这些图展示的另外一点是
tighter as the experiment size increases.
实验规模越大 分布越紧密
It is hard to see that from the actual width of the distributions,
你很难从实际的分布宽度来发现这一点
since these plots are scaled to the range of the values.
因为这些图是按照值的范围进行缩放的
However, if you look at the actual range of values on the x axis,
然而 你看看 x 轴上的实际值的范围
you can see that the smallest experiment,
你可以看到最小实验中
the differences ranged from negative 0.15, to positive 0.15.
差异范围从负 0.15 至正 0.15
While for the medium experiments, the range was from negative 0.09 to positive
中型实验中 范围为负 0.09 至正 0.09
0.09, and for the large, it was from negative .03 to positive .03.
而大型实验 范围为负 0.03 至正 0.03
So these distributions are definitely getting tighter as the sample size
所以当样本量增加时 分布一定会变得更紧密
increases, which is in line with what we expected.
这符合我们的预期